# **Kristen Lucas**

# **Data Analyst**

Nashville, TN 37208

Phone: 520-548-9690

Email: kristenw629@gmail.com

github - https://github.com/KristenLucas

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/kristen-lucas-b1520311a/

# **Professional Profile**

Data Analyst with a passion for using data to create understandable visuals to help make sound business decisions. Motivated, versatile worker with over 15 years of experience the workplace. Proven record of excellence in fast-paced, often chaotic, environments. Especially skilled at creating and following a goal-oriented plan while making necessary adaptations to ensure an excellent result. While getting a job done well, who ever said you can't have fun at the same time?! We are living in a world where data is the future, and I'm excited to be a part of it.

# **Technical Skills**

- SQL PostgreSQL, BigQuery
- Advanced Excel experience
- Intermediate Python ability
- Effective Visualizations Power BI, Tableau, Excel

# Other Skills

- Full Microsoft Suite knowledge/ability
- Github, including Kanban boards
- SalesForce & Outreach experience
- Clear communication
- Effective storytelling

# **Data Analytics Experience**

#### **Nashville Software School**

Grad Date - Jan 2020

Six month, intensive, apprenticeship school focused on practical training in data analysis using real-world projects and visualizations.

### Projects (Github's are linked):

# Nashville 911 Calls and Dispatch (Python, Excel)

Our entire class performed an analysis of 911 calls and dispatch data during some of the most devastating natural disasters in Nashville in recent years: The tornados on March 3<sup>rd</sup>, 2020, and the derecho on May 3<sup>rd</sup>, 2020. We mapped many things including the times of calls vs dispatch, most affected areas by zip code, and any correlation between COVID-19 and these events. We were split into 4 teams and I led my team and managed our Kanban board to ensure all tasks were completed in the proper time.

# Nashville Cemetery (Excel)

Analysis of the cemetery and those buried there. We were able to analyze the ages, races, and reasons for death for all of whom there are records. My team created a visually dynamic dashboard to present the information.

#### Lahman Baseball (PostgresSQL)

Analysis of baseball players, managers, stats, salaries, and more from the years 1876-2016. This project consisted of 27 tables and required multiple joins on most queries.

# **Work Experience**

#### Sip Café - Nashville, TN

Aug 2019 – Present

Local café in East Nashville specializing in locally roasted coffee and house-made ice cream.

#### Barista/Shift Leader

- Multi-task quickly to fill orders for beverages and baked goods.
- Effectively work as part of a team to ensure efficiency and customer satisfaction.
- Maintain high level of excellence in fast-paced environment.
- Continually organize and clean workspace.
- While shift leading, ensure that all baristas have completed side work in a timely manner.
- Track tips and money throughout day.

#### Ramsey Solutions - Nashville, TN

July 2016 - Aug 2019

Nashville based financial solutions company focused on helping people in every walk of life to better their finances.

#### **Real Estate ELP- Customer Advocate**

- Managed my own calendar to maintain daily call goal of 40-90 (changed throughout duration of position).
- Return or respond to all voicemails and emails within 24 hours.
- Assisted in the training of 5 new team members.
- Attend weekly Sales Training meetings.
- Effectively overcome objects by using the skills I learned in Sales Training.
- Brainstorm with teammates to overcome obstacles and pivot as needed.
- Determine concerns from customers and intervene to resolve.

# Central City Assembly of God - Tucson, AZ

Aug 2010 - May 2016

Church in Tucson of around 100 members.

#### Associate Pastor/Administrator

- Analyzed finances and created yearly budget that increased our capacity by double.
- Manage volunteers.
- Manage volunteers during weekly gatherings and outreaches.
- Assist Lead Pastor in any capacity necessary.

### Raging Sage Coffee Roaster - Tucson, AZ

Sept 2011 - May 2016

Local coffee shop specializing in coffee roasted in-house and baked goods made in-house.

#### Assistant Manager (July 2012-May 2016)

- Create policies for daily operations to ensure maximum efficiency.
- Ensure employee adherence to store protocols.
- Serve as liaison between manager and staff.
- Maintain organization of merchandise and office areas.
- Assist manager in the process of hiring by conducting both face-to-face and working interviews.
- Function as lead trainer.

#### Barista/Baker (Sept 2011-May 2016)

- Multi-task quickly to fill orders
- for beverages and baked goods.
- Effectively work as part of a team to ensure efficiency and customer satisfaction.
- Maintain high level of excellence in fast-paced environment.
- Continually organize and clean workspace.
- Follow specific instructions to create locally famous baked goods.

# Teen Challenge's Springboard Home for Youth in Crisis - Tucson, AZ

Jan 2011 - May 2016

Group recovery home for girls ages 12-17.

# **Group Home Houseparent**

- Recorded daily observations of residents for reference by counselors.
- Enforced group home polices.
- Ensured adherence to daily schedule and tasks.
- Maintained proper distribution and documentation of medications.
- Maintained confidentiality in accordance with state law.

### Education

Nashville Software School Expected Graduation:

Jan 2021

Berean School of the Bible Aug 2011 – Aug 2013

**Global University correspondence** 

Assembly of God Certification Credentials

Master's Commission USA Sept 2006 – May 2010

Ministry apprenticeship program. I was a student for 2 years, then on staff for 2 years.